Guide to the 275th Anniversary Commemoration, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
275th Anniversary Commemoration, Yale University, records
1923-1977
RU 15
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
Yale University celebrated its 275th anniversary on 15 October 1976. The records primarily consist of background materials, drafts and transcripts of ceremonial remarks, and writings by invited speakers, including a commemorative poem by Archibald Macleish.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the President.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of the President, May 1977.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject, name, or form of material.
Scope and Contents
Yale University celebrated its 275th anniversary on 15 October 1976. The records primarily consist of background materials, drafts and transcripts of ceremonial remarks, and writings by invited speakers, including a commemorative poem by Archibald Macleish.
Anniversaries; Yale University -- Anniversaries, etc.
- 275th commemoration records, Series I
  - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Haskins, Caryl P. to Kingman Brewster, Jr., enclosure: preliminary draft of ceremony remarks, 1976 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Macleish, Archibald
    - Background material for 275th anniversary poem, 1923-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3-7)
      General
      See also: Warch, Richard: letter with enclosures, box 1 folder 14
    - Correspondence regarding 275th anniversary poem, 1976 July-August (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Various writings, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pierson, George W. to Kingman Brewster, Jr., enclosure: text of speech, "Yale's 275th Birthday"; text of program for 275th Anniversary ceremony with corrections, typescript, 1976 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Program and invitation to 275th anniversary ceremony, 1976 Oct 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Talbot, Strobe to Kingman Brewster, Jr., enclosure: text of remarks for program, 1976 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Text of anniversary ceremony with corrections, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Warch, Richard to Kingman Brewster, Jr., with enclsoures: xerox copies of biographies of Yale men, 1976 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    General note
    See also: Macleish, Archibald, Background material for 275th anniversary poem, box 1, folders 3-7